Robert S. Savelson Collection of National Union Merger Agreements 6975
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
Robert S. Savelson Collection of National Union Merger Agreements
1955-2002
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
Savelson, Robert S.
6975
0.5 cubic feet
0.5 linear ft.
Records.
This collection consists of nineteen merger agreements between national unions collected by Robert Savelson.
16213829
General
Contact Information:
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives Martin P. Catherwood Library 227 Ives Hall Cornell University Ithaca, NY 14853 (607) 255-3183 kheel_center@cornell.edu http://www.ilr.cornell.edu/library/kheel-center
Compiled by:
E. Parker, March 21, 2018
EAD encoding:
E. Parker, March 22, 2018
Conditions Governing Access
Access to the collections in the Kheel Center is restricted. Please contact a reference archivist for access to these materials.
Labor unions -- Mergers; Savelson, Robert S.; Newspaper Guild; Communications Workers of America; National Association of Broadcast Employees and Technicians; International Union of Electronic, Electrical, Salaried, Machine & Furniture Workers-Communications Workers of America; International Typographic Union; United Steelworkers of America; United Rubber, Cork, Linoleum, and Plastic Workers of America; Upholsterers' International Union of North America; Retail, Wholesale, and Department Store Union; United Paperworkers International Union; Oil, Chemical, and Atomic Workers International Union; United Food and Commercial Workers International Union; International Organization of Masters, Mates, and Pilots; International Longshoremen's Association; Retail Clerks International Union; Amalgamated Meat Cutters and Butcher Workmen of North America; Textile Workers Union of America; Amalgamated Clothing Workers of America; International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union; Amalgamated Clothing and Textile Workers Union; Committee of Interns and Residents (New York, N.Y.); Service Employees International Union; Screen Actors Guild; American Federation of Television and Radio Artists
16213829
- Listings of Mergers, New Affiliates, Title Changes, etc. Since Merger December 1955, 2002 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Agreement for Affiliation and Merger between The Newspaper Guild, AFL-CIO, CLC and the Communications Workers of America, AFL-CIO, CLC (Box 1, Folder 2)
  Scope and Contents
  Undated
- Agreement for Affiliation and Merger between the National Association of Broadcast Employees and Technicians, AFL-CIO and the Communications Workers of America, AFL-CIO, 1992 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Agreement for the Merger Between International Union of Electronic, Electrical, Salaried, Machine and Furniture Workers, AFL-CIO and the Communications Workers of America, AFL-CIO, CLC, 2000 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Agreement for Merger and Affiliation between the International Typographic Union, AFL-CIO, CLC and the Communication Workers of America, AFL-CIO, 1986 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  (2 copies)
- Merger Agreement Between the United Steelworkers of America and the United Rubber, Cork, Linoleum & Plastic Workers of America, 1995 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Proposed Merger Agreement between the Upholsterers' International Union and the United Steelworkers of America, 1985 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  UIU Journal article
- Merger Agreement Between United Steelworkers of America and Retail, Wholesale and Department Store Union/Canada, 1993 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Merger Agreement as adopted by the International Executive Boards of the United Paperworkers International Union and the Oil, Chemical and Atomic Workers International Union, 1998 (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Merger Agreement of the Retail, Wholesale and Department Store Union, AFL-CIO, CLC and the United Food and Commercial Workers International Union, AFL-CIO, CLC, 1993 (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Affiliation of the International Organization of Masters, Mates and Pilots with the International Longshoremen's Association, 1976 (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Merger Agreement of the Retail Clerks International Union and Amalgamated Meat Cutters and Butcher Workmen, 1979 (Box 1, Folder 12)
- Agreement and Plan of Merger and Consolidation between the Textile Workers Union of America and the Amalgamated Clothing Workers of America, 1976 (Box 1, Folder 13)
- Merger Agreement Between the International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union and the Amalgamated Clothing and Textile Workers' Union, 1995 (Box 1, Folder 14)
- Annotated Affiliation Agreement between the Committee of Interns and Residents and the Service Employees International Union, AFL-CIO, CLC, 2000 (Box 1, Folder 15)
- Agreement and Plan of Merger between the Screen Actors guild and the American Federation of Television and Radio Artists, 1995 (Box 1, Folder 16)
- Report and Recommendations of the Joint AFL-CIO Unity Committee, 1955 (Box 1, Folder 17)